Hey, Blade!
The least you could do is draw your sword!
Don't disrespect your opponents
by looking away during a fight!
You look a little different.
D-Do I?
In what way?
Oh!
Ah!
No idea!
Take notice when a lady
changes up her hairstyle!
Huh? Oh, was that it?
It's not like I wanted you to notice...
Oh yeah, Blade.
If you've got time to horse around
with the likes of Leonard,
can you also keep an eye on that girl?
The likes of me?!
That girl?
Ah, you mean Sophie?
The likes of...?! How heartless!
Why's she by herself?
Ignored!
That's how she always is.
Even though she obeys any
commands she's given.
Is that so?
Yeah.
But I've never seen her take
any spontaneous action.
And yet, she voluntarily told you her name.
That's why I'm leaving her to you, Blade.
Got it.
You need to build up more stamina!
Run ten kilometers every morning
for the rest of your life!
My whole life?
Yo! I'm Blade!
I know.
Earnest asked me to watch over your training!
Is that a command?
Well, that's not what I meant.
I guess it's true that she asked me...
I'm here because I want to help you.
But... this is all I can use.
Why barehanded?
This is all I was taught.
In that case, I'll teach
you other ways to fight.
Is that a command?
Nope.
I want to lend you a hand as your friend!
It's not a command,
so I won't force you into it.
Are you against the idea?
No, I'm not.
It's settled, then!
Okay, first off...
All right, that's it for
today's practical training!
Huh?! Why?!
We were just getting started!
It's because you took your sweet time!
No way...
Episode 2
Sophie
I can't cut through it.
Channel your fighting spirit into the sword.
You have no problem channeling
it into your fists, right?
Then think of the sword as
an extension of your body.
Like this.
Understood.
I managed to cut them.
You sure learn fast!
If you can handle a sword like this,
I think you're set.
Let's call it a day.
Can I beat her now?
Eh?
Who do you mean?
Earnest.
Well...
I don't know about that.
Getting to her level won't be so easy...
I see.
Huh?
This is stronger.
Guess you're right.
By the way, I can't move.
It wouldn't be a good mount position
if the opponent could move freely.
Good point.
I want you to teach me
something else tomorrow.
Yeah, sure thing!
How's your school life going?
I made some friends.
I'm glad to hear that.
You've been active as a hero
since you were three years old.
Even I have someone I consider my best friend,
while you, on the other hand...
Well, sorry!
I really am so glad.
So, who exactly is it you call your friend?
There's more than one...
But recently, I guess... Sophie.
Oh...
I should have known you'd
take an interest in her.
She's a strong one, wouldn't you say?
Yeah, she's strong.
Even so, she's still incomplete.
What?
After all, the goal was for her
completed form to surpass you.
What are you talking about?!
You didn't befriend her because you knew?
About the Artificial Great Hero Project?
Artificial Great Hero?
If you, the Great Hero, can exist,
it should also be possible to
create a being just like you.
That was the idea proposed
by a certain group.
With ancient forbidden
knowledge that had been lost,
they took a human who showed
aptitude as a template,
and tried to artificially manifest
the Great Hero's powers.
What's more, they duplicated
that original human
in order to perform countless
experiments and adjustments.
Hold on...
Hold on just one minute!
Duplicated?
I thought we were talking about Sophie!
Her real name is Sophitia Femto.
Femto meaning "twelve."
That is to say, she's the twelfth iteration
of the human named Sophitia.
As an experimental subject, she was
treated for so long as simply an object.
Hey, don't tell me that those experiments...
No need for concern!
I've completely put an
end to that organization.
If it wasn't your doing,
you should have said so.
When I took her in, I told
her that she was free now.
She responded with...
Is that a command?
I expect that hasn't changed.
Sophie was robbed of a normal life
for the sake of creating a Great Hero.
It's my fault.
It's all because I exist.
In that case...
I'll make sure Sophie gets
her normal life back!
But...
What is normal, anyway?
Oh, what's wrong?
You're not scheduled for
your check-up just yet.
Did you want me to look you over?
In that case, take off your clothes.
Take them off right now.
Please tell me!
What does being normal mean?
What kinds of things do
kids my age normally do?!
So you're finally interested
in exploring that subject.
I don't mind.
I'll teach you everything there is
to know about the vigor of youth—
Got it!
So it's youth!
What is it, Blade?
Youth! What does youth mean?
What does it involve?!
I'm not sure where this came from...
But when you think of youth,
it'd have to be...
Love, perhaps?
Got it!
So it's love!
Go!
Blade?
What's the matter?
Please tell me!
What is love?
What do you do when you're in love?!
What? Love?!
W-Well...
Go on! Out with it!
Things like... going on dates together—
Got it!
So it's dates!
Why'd you suddenly come up to my room?
Earnest!
What's a date?
What exactly do you do?!
A date?!
H-H-Hold on a moment, Blade!
Please tell me!
I'm begging you, Earnest!
Eh?!
That's, well...
Couples spend time alone talking,
walk around town, go shopping...
B-But we're not at that level yet...
I think it's still a little
too early for a date...
Got it!
I'm off on a date!
Huh? Wait...
With who exactly?!
Step step step.
Where's Sophie?!
Sophie's still inside—
Thanks!
Huh?! Wait!
Sophie!
What?!
Blade?!
Sophie!
Let's go on a date!
Is that a command?
No, it's not.
But it's very important!
I understand.
Yes, officer, this man right here.
Blade barged into the girls' shower...
A lot of girls have filed complaints.
What in the world's gotten into that idiot?
I'll have to sternly steer
him down the right path.
Red bean bun!
Huh?
Here, Claire.
Please take one too, Empress.
Thank you.
Bread?
What is this? It's so sweet!
It is a red bean bun.
Have you never had one before?
O-O-Of course I have!
So sweet!
So even the Empress makes faces like that.
H-Hey, you two...
Can you stop it with the whole Empress thing?
Lady Earnest, then?
Not that, either!
Just call me Earnest.
O-Oh, no! We couldn't possibly!
Right now, we're comrades
united by our mission,
to watch Blade so he doesn't
try any funny business.
You could...
p-practically say that we're friends!
Yep.
You're right.
Ah, it's almost time.
Oh, you're right on time.
Is that not normal?
I don't know anything about dates.
That's fine.
Leave everything to me!
I did loads of studying for this!
Okay, let's review our agenda for today.
Assemble at 1000 hours.
Salute and briefing at 1001 hours.
Begin mobilizing at 1003 hours.
Patrol town until 1030 hours.
Afterwards, R&R at a parlor until 1100 hours.
Lunch time starting at 1200 hours.
Further agenda items to follow at lunch time!
Isn't that a little too precise?
This sounds less like a date...
And more like a spec ops mission!
It's already 1004 hours.
Oh, no! What do we do?!
The agenda! The agenda!
We just need to begin mobilizing now.
Ah, that's right!
W-Walking arm in arm? How indecent!
That's totally normal.
Calm down, Anna.
Anna?
It's a nickname, since we're friends.
Should I call you something else?
I'm fine with Anna!
Ah!
I lost sight of them.
Heave-ho.
Look, look!
Oh, wow.
They're eating it!
I want to try feeding them.
Okay! Just you wait!
Let's dump it in.
There!
Too much! There's too much!
What's with the date-like activities?!
They are on a date.
There they go.
Heave-ho.
I just need to punch this?
Okay, on the count of two.
Are you ready?
I-I'll have you know...
I'm perfectly capable of this much!
Th-That aside...
W-We need to stop them!
One, two!
Aw, man, they've done it now.
We're so sorry! We're so sorry!
You can send the bill to Rosewood Academy...
Heave-ho.
Our next mission is to finish this
Lovely Infinite Tropical Drink together!
I just need to drink this?
Wait!
It's only 1029 hours!
We've still got one minute!
I'm thirsty.
Well... that's fine, then.
It's hard to sip this.
Come a little closer.
S-Sure.
What's wrong?
Well, I'm not sure...
But it feels...
Feels...
I can't complete this mission by myself.
I need your help.
I-I know.
I know that!
Be still, my beating heart!
Come a little closer.
My heart... My heart...
They haven't noticed us at all.
I think I've gotten sick of this.
How obscene! Dirty! Impure!
Filthy animals!
Their cheeks are touching!
Here, Anna.
You can have this.
Cheeks cheekily chafing...
So cool and sweet!
What is this yummy treat?!
It's called a parfait.
Yum yum!
So are you done now?
With what?
They've already left.
Heave-ho.
What's wrong?
Well, it felt like we were being followed...
Oh well.
Blade, you moron!
Anyway, next on the agenda...
Oh, no! Look at the time!
It's fine.
We can take a shortcut.
Is this our final target?
I heard this is a legendary fountain.
I don't really understand.
Me, neither.
I had fun today.
Well...
Can I ask one thing?
What is it?
Why are you going to all this trouble?
Why, you ask...
That's because...
you're my friend.
You and I are friends?
That's right!
You bet we are!
I heard friends don't keep
secrets from each other.
Well, I...
There's something I haven't told you.
Huh?
If you and I are friends...
If you're willing to be my friend...
there's something I need to tell you.
I'm not an ordinary human.
An incomplete test subject,
created to be an artificial hero.
I was granted what are known as
Artificial Great Hero Powers.
Artificial... Great Hero Powers?
Look.
Great Hero Powers can
alter the laws of physics.
However...
I have incomplete control of them.
Gravity manipulation...
I magnified my body weight by 1,000
times... or that was my intent.
This is actually around 10,000 times.
Sophie.
I can even stop time itself.
As I am now...
I can manifest Artificial Great
Hero Powers for just ten seconds.
Sophitia Femto.
The twelfth clone of a woman named Sophitia.
That is what I am.
The final model of the
Artificial Great Hero Project,
and its sole success, with caveats.
In that case, I won't
keep any secrets, either.
Please listen.
I'm listening.
I'm...
They call me...
They call me... the Great Hero!
No, they used to call me that.
Those powers are gone now.
I see.
Could it be that you realized?
No.
But something about you felt familiar.
I'm really sorry.
It's not something that an apology
and forgiveness can fix...
Feel free to resent me.
Why would I do that?
Because the reason you were born
with such accursed powers...
Accursed?
That's right!
This power is a curse!
I never...
The Great Hero wasn't
something I asked to be!
But because they said I could save everyone,
that's why there was no choice but to do it!
With powers that manifested
at the age of three...
Fighting monsters,
fighting them again and again...
Lingering between life and
death countless times...
And growing strong.
Even so, not every single
person can be rescued.
There are those who couldn't be saved!
People get so angry when
you can't save someone!
Why didn't you save them?
Why?!
Aren't you the Great Hero?!
It's... It's...
The Great Hero...
What does it mean to be the Great Hero?
Blade.
Even if you didn't choose to be,
you were the Great Hero.
After being rescued by the king,
I left on a journey to find out who I was.
People saved by the Great Hero.
Entire towns.
I came across so many.
You should be proud of that.
That's impossible.
I see.
It's fine if you can't.
However...
I take pride in the fact that I was
created to be an Artificial Great Hero.
What?
I want to become like you.
That's... That's...
No, I...
won't let my past as the
Great Hero bother me!
Yes.
If that's what you decide, then that's fine.
Your identity as the Great Hero...
is the secret we share.
Yeah, it's a promise.
Just between the two of us.
Next Time
Cu Chulainn